imedix.com 2008-12-21

# iMedix - Privacy policy

We respect your privacy. This policy explains the accepted privacy practices for our website at [www.iMedix.com](http://www.imedix.com/) (" **iMedix** "). It describes the ways we collect and use your personal information on iMedix and the rights and options available to you with respect to your information. This policy is incorporated to the iMedix's Terms of Use (the " **Terms of Use** " or the " **Terms** "). 

[](http://www.truste.org/ivalidate.php?url=www.imedix.com&sealid=101) iMedix Inc. is a licensee of the TRUSTe Web Privacy Seal Program. TRUSTe is an independent, non-profit organization whose mission is to build user's trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the use of fair information practices. This privacy statement covers the Web site [www.iMedix.com](http://www.imedix.com/). Because this Web site wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact us at [support@imedix.com](mailto:support@imedix.com). If you do not receive acknowledgement of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should contact TRUSTe at <http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php> TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison with us to resolve your concerns. 

**Personal Information that we collect**  
When you register with iMedix, we may ask you to provide us with personal details such as your name and e-mail address. We collect further information when you use any of the services on iMedix (the "Services"). We collect personally identifiable information at various points on our site. We collect information such as your name, email address, and date of birth when you register on our site, report inappropriate content, send feedback, invite a friend, and use our BLOG among other services.

We also record the frequency and scope of your use of the Services, the duration of your sessions, the web pages that you visit, information that you read, content that you use or create, advertisements that you view or click on, your communications with other users and third parties on iMedix, the Internet protocol (IP) address and the name of the domain that serve you to access iMedix, or any of the Services, and the geographic location of the computer system that you are using to log-in on iMedix through the use of "cookies" and "log files" (See "Cookies" and "Log Files" below). 

**Cookies**  
We use cookies on iMedix. Cookies are packets of information sent by our servers to your web browser and then sent back by the browser each time it accesses our servers. The cookies contain a variety of information, such as the content of search queries, iMedix's pages you have accessed, session durations and IP addresses. We use cookies for various purposes, such as to save you the need to re-enter your user name and password each time you log-in on iMedix, to facilitate the use of services on iMedix, to collect statistical information with respect to the use of iMedix, to verify information, to customize services on iMedix to your personal preferences and for information security purposes. 

Some of the Cookies may expire when the session ends and you exit your browser. Other cookies are saved on your computer's hard drive for the purposes above. If you wish to block our cookies, then please use the help button in your browser and follow the necessary instructions. However, bear in mind that disabling cookies may complicate or even prevent your use of iMedix, or certain features thereof. 

Some of our business partners (e.g., advertisers) use cookies on our site. We have no access to or control over these cookies. See "Third Party Advertisers" below.

This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by [www.imedix.com](http://www.imedix.com/) only and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

**Log Files**  
As is true of most Web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data. 

The information we gather via log files may be anonymous or in some instances personally identifiable. If you are not a registered user, than we will not knowingly make use of any information which personally identifies you, except as specifically indicated in the policy with reference to anonymous tracking data collection.

Further information may be collected when we exchange communications with you, for example, if you submit a request to our customer support, or when you contact our designated Copyright Agent. 

We use this information to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users' movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. 

We do link this automatically-collected data to personally identifiable information as indicated above for the purposes of troubleshooting and statistics. 

We use a third-party tracking service that uses cookies to track non-personally identifiable information about visitors to our site in the aggregate to capture, e.g. usage and volume statistics. 

**Communications from the Site –**

 _Special Offers and Updates_

We will occasionally send you information on products, services, special deals and promotions. You can sign up for these emails from your on our personal settings page.   
Out of respect for your privacy, we present the option not to receive these types of communications. Please see the "Choice and Opt-out." 

_Service-related Announcements_

We will send you service-related announcements, on a regular basis. For instance we will notify you through e-mail that you have a message waiting for your attention in your iMedix inbox.   
Out of respect for your privacy, we provide you a way to unsubscribe. Please see the "Choice and Opt-out" section.

 _Maintenance-related announcements_

We will send you strictly maintenance-related announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an email.   
Generally, you may not opt-out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature. If you do not wish to receive them, you have the option to deactivate your account by contacting us at [support@imedix.com](mailto:support@imedix.com)  

**Choice/Opt-out**  
We provide you the opportunity to 'opt-out' of having your personally identifiable information used for certain purposes, when we ask for this information. 

For instance, if you no longer wish to receive our promotional communications or our service related announcements, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each communication or by emailing us at your personal settings page, or you may contact us at [support@imedix.com](mailto:support@imedix.com) to opt-out.

You will be notified when we have explicitly authorized that your personally identifiable information will be collected by any third party that is not our agent/service provider, in cases other than voluntary exchange of information with other users, so you can make an informed choice as to whether or not to share your information with that party.

**Live Chat Feature/Private Messaging**  
If you use a the chat feature on this site, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit while using the live chat feature. 

**Private Messaging**  
The Private messaging service allows you to communicate with other users through iMedix, including sending and receiving messages in and to your private inbox. This service is available to registered members only. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit while using this service. 

_Invite-A-Friend_

If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our site, we will ask you for your friend's name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. iMedix stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and tracking the success of our referral program. 

**Personal information that you share**  
iMedix enables you to upload your medical and health related content and share it with other users, without revealing your identity. The content that you upload, including text and images, will be accessible to other users and may appear in search results on iMedix. This information is uploaded to your sign-up page, your personal profile and your blog.   
You must exercise caution and common sense when uploading your content, especially any personally identifiable information. At the very least you should demonstrate the same degree of caution as when publishing your content by any means other than the Internet.

 _BLOG_

We will enable you to start and operate a personal blog on iMedix. If you use our BLOG on this site, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of this forum, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in this forum. 

**What do we do with your personally identifiable information?**   
We may use personally identifiable information for the following purposes only:  

  * to enable you to use iMedix and to provide you with the Services;
  * to improve and customize your experience on iMedix;
  * to provide you with support, handle complaints;
  * to send you service related updates and notices, to provide you with information pertaining to the Services and to provide you with further marketing and advertising material, _subject to your prior indication of consent on iMedix_. At any time you may opt out of our mailing lists, by changing your preferences in your iMedix personal account or by following the unsubscribe instructions included in each email sent to you. In any case, we will not share your personal identifiable details with any third parties, without your explicit consent; 
  * to post your content on iMedix and to facilitate communication between you and us, and between you and other users;
  * to enforce the Terms of Use;
  * to contact you as and when we believe it to be necessary for service related issues;
  * to comply with any applicable law and assist law enforcement agencies under any applicable law;
  * to collect fees and debts, and to prevent fraud, misappropriation, infringements, identity thefts and any other misuse of iMedix; 
  * to take any action in any case of dispute, or legal proceeding of any kind between you and us, or between you and other users or third parties with respect to, or in relation with iMedix;

**How do we use aggregated information?**  
We use anonymous, statistical or aggregated information on iMedix, including posting, disseminating, transmitting or otherwise communicating or making available such information through iMedix, or to users on iMedix, or to our suppliers, partners and any other third party, at our sole discretion, provided however, that such information will not identify you personally and that we will not knowingly, or intentionally use such information to reveal your identity without your consent, under the terms of this policy. We use Google Analytics and Google Ad sense. We have no physical or legal control over the use of this information by such providers. 

We also use anonymous, statistical or aggregated information to properly operate iMedix, to improve the quality of the Services, to enhance your experience, to create new services, including customized services, to change or cancel existing content or services and for further internal and statistical purposes. 

**Sharing information with others**  
We do not sell, rent or lease your personally identifiable information to third parties for any purpose including their own marketing purposes except as stated in this privacy policy.   
We share personally identifiable information with others in any of the following instances, or subject to your explicit consent:   

  * When you use the Services, or when you take part in any content-related activity, or request for a third party's service through iMedix, or when you use such service. In these cases, we will share your information only to the extent required to facilitate your use of the services;
  * If we reasonably believe that you have breached iMedix's Terms of Use, or abused your rights to use iMedix, or performed any act or omission that we reasonably believe to be violating any applicable law, rules, or regulations. We may share your information in these cases, with law enforcement and other competent authorities and with any third party, as may be required to handle any result of your wrongdoing;
  * If we are compelled, or reasonably believe that we are compelled by law to share or disclose your information to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Web site.
  * In any case of dispute, or legal proceeding of any kind between you and us, or between you and other users or third parties with respect to, or in relation with iMedix;
  * In any case where we may reasonably believe that sharing information is necessary to prevent imminent physical damage or damage to property;
  * If we organize the operation of iMedix within a different framework, or through another legal structure or entity, or if we are acquired by, or merged with another entity, provided however, that those entities agree to be bound by the provisions of this policy, with respective changes taken into consideration; 
  * We may also share personally identifiable information with companies or organizations connected, or affiliated with us, such as subsidiaries, sister-companies and parent companies. Such information sharing will be subject to the transferees warrantee that they will use such information in full compliance with this privacy policy _and only for the purposes consented to by the user._

**Accessing your personal information on iMedix**  
At any time you may access your account on iMedix and edit, or amend your personal information by updating your profile on the site. If you find that the information on your account is not accurate, complete or updated, than you must make all necessary changes to correct it here Please keep in mind that false, incorrect, or out dated information may prevent you from registering with iMedix and impair our ability to provide you with Services and to contact you. You may also deactivate your account by contacting us at [support@imedix.com](mailto:support@imedix.com).

Prior to accessing personal information on behalf of another person, we may ask you to provide us with a written and duly signed power of attorney, specifically confirming that you are authorized by the personal information's subject, or the subject's legal guardian, to access the information and edit, or amend it. You agree that we may deny you access, if you fail to provide us with the necessary power of attorney. 

**Links to Other Sites**  
This Web site contains links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by Imedix Inc. Please be aware that we, Imedix Inc., are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information.

This privacy statement applies only to information collected by this Web site. 

**Data retention**  
We reserve the right at all times to review, retain and/or disclose any information as we deem necessary to satisfy any applicable law, regulation, legal process or governmental request. However, by doing so we do not either expressly or impliedly endorse, affirm or in any manner assume any responsibility for such communications. 

**Third Party Advertisers**  
We permit certain other companies to conduct advertising campaigns on iMedix (serve ads on the site). The advertisements that you see when accessing iMedix are redirected from the servers of those advertising companies. Some advertisers may use cookies on your computer. The cookies enable them to collect information about websites that you have accessed, advertisements posted on those sites and the advertisements that you have viewed. In this manner advertisers try to customize advertisements to your preferences. The advertisers' use of cookies is subject to their own privacy policies and not to this Policy. If you wish to study the privacy policies of those advertisers you should visit their websites, or contact them directly. We have no access or control of the third party cookies used by advertisers. 

**Information Security**  
We implement systems, applications and procedures to secure your personal information, to minimize the risks of theft, damage, loss of information, or unauthorized access or use of information. However, these measures are unable to provide absolute assurance. Therefore, although we take great efforts to protect your privacy, we do not guarantee and you cannot reasonably expect that iMedix and our databases will be immune from any wrongdoings, malfunctions, unlawful interceptions or access, or other kinds of abuse and misuse, or that your private communications on or through iMedix will remain private. 

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**  
We may change and update the terms of this Policy from time to time. We therefore recommend that you read it periodically. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a prominent notice on our home page. These material changes will take effect 30 days following this notice. 

**Contact us**  
You may send us requests, responses, questions and complaints, by using the 'contact us' form on iMedix, or by contacting us at [support@imedix.com](mailto:support@imedix.com) (iMedix Inc., 511 Avenue of the Americas # 641.New York, NY 10011-8436). 

Last Updated: November 15, 2007
